<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>PolyMC</title>
	<subtitle>An Open Source Minecraft launcher with the ability to manage multiple instances, accounts and mods. Focused on user freedom and free redistributability.</subtitle>
	
	<link href="https://polymc.org/polymc.org/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://polymc.org/"/>
	<updated>2022-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://polymc.org/</id>
	<author>
		<name>PolyMC</name>
		<email>youremailaddress@example.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Modrinth support and Mod downloading</title>
		<link href="https://polymc.org/polymc.org/news/moddownload/"/>
		<updated>2022-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://polymc.org/polymc.org/news/moddownload/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @timoreo it is now possible to download individual mods from both cursforge and modrinth this pull request is the first of many big changes coming to PolyMC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshots of the new feature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/81902668/152801619-8d826540-2467-4973-9488-f6afcb7ba804.png&quot; alt=&quot;ModInstallBlack&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/81902668/152801625-e7ad87f7-464f-49a2-ab4f-116f592acec1.png&quot; alt=&quot;ModInstallWhite&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>New maintainers and step down.</title>
		<link href="https://polymc.org/polymc.org/news/newmantainers/"/>
		<updated>2022-02-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://polymc.org/polymc.org/news/newmantainers/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Based off recent contoversy lead maintainer swurl has decided to step down from their role as maintainer. Lenny is now the head maintainer of PolyMC and has established a new core group of maintainers to keep the project healthy and active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Swurl Stated&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@here Based on recent controversies, and in thinking of the general    future of this project, I believe it to be best if I step down from my leadership position in PolyMC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenny will now be maintaining PolyMC and all its related services, and will be establishing a core team to help with development resources and community management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, due to mental health and other personal reasons, I will be taking a break from--and generally will be unavailable for--contributing to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for providing me a great community to work with. I pray for PolyMC to have a good future and for all of you to continue to do good for the Free Software community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quote in news: &lt;a href=&quot;https://discordapp.com/channels/923671181020766230/923672379144671263/939731859431100416&quot;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://matrix.to/#/!oOkwnJBCfVOMgEOp:polymc.org/$yGu0hoOB36_bSVPnV8msXAHl7or12JHch7axAoCe-RY?via=polymc.org&amp;amp;via=swirl.funny.cl&amp;amp;via=matrix.org&quot;&gt;Element&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swurl contributed a lot to PolyMC and is an incredibly talented programmer. They will be missed and we hope to keep PolyMC always active and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In lighter news congratulations to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scumplex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timoreo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;txtsd&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dada513&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tabzlock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cozyGalvinism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are all apart of the PolyMC &amp;quot;Core Team&amp;quot; The core team maintain the PolyMc project and repositorys around it. We hope to see great contributions and continued development of PolyMC.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
